Light-kun... is the first friend I've ever had.
月君は…
私の初めての友達ですから
Misa?
海砂…
Yes?
はい
Can you ask Rem to kill L?
レムに頼んでくれるか？
L を殺せって…
Rem, I want to be loved by Light.
レム、ライトに愛されたい
I'll be happy.
それが、私の幸せ
Okay...
いいだろう
I'll kill L.
L を殺してやるよ
L is going to die... just like that?
L が死ぬ…
こんな簡単に…
Gamble
So, when do you want him killed?
で、いつ殺す？
If you take me to him, I'll kill him instantly.
そいつの居場所に連れて行ってもらえれば、すぐに殺せるが
The earlier, the better. It could even be tomorrow.
早い方がいい
明日にも…
Then again, it may be a little careless to decide straight away.
しかし、今すぐ決断するのは安易だな
Tonight, I'll think carefully about when and how we should kill him, and I'll give you my answer after that.
今晩、殺し方と合わせて、よく考えてから返事する
I understand.
わかった
Listen. No matter what happens, don't kill until I give the signal.
いいか、いかなる場合でも、僕が指示するまでは殺すな
No matter what happens!
「いかなる場合でも」だ
ああ、それは約束してやるよ
Sure, I can promise you that... with regard to L...
L に関しては…
Misa, give me your cell phone number.
海砂、携帯の番号を教えてくれ
You're rather slow on the uptake!
今頃遅いよ
Give me yours too.
ライトのも教えてね
No, I can't give you mine.
いや、僕の番号は教えられない
Why?!
何でよ！恋人同士でそんなのない
You can't do that when you're part of a couple!
I already told you, I'm being marked by the police.
僕は警察にマークされてると言っただろう
These days, they have the ability to bug specific telephone lines.
今の警察は、特定者電話の会話を聞く事ができるんだ
Oh! In that case, have this!
あっ、じゃ、だったらこれ
Misa will give you one of hers!
海砂の携帯一個あげる
After I started to use each for a different purpose, I ended up with three!
色々使い分けてたら、三個になったから
It's a good idea.
いいアイデアだ
Yours should probably be fine.
海砂のなら多分大丈夫だろう
Yay! I'll give you a love call every day!
やった
毎日ラブコールするね、メールもたくさん
And send you lots of texts!
No, I'll be leaving the phone switched off.
いや、電源は切っておく
電話する時は最低限必要なことを、こっちからのみだ
I'll call you only when necessary, and ensure that information is kept to a minimum.
え、そんな…
No way... when will you call me?
いつ電話してくれる？
Probably tomorrow.
多分明日…
L を処刑するしないに関わらず、一度連絡入れるよ
Regardless of whether we go ahead with killing L or not, I'll give you a call.
Yay! Tomorrow?!
ええ～明日
Doesn't sound like the call is going to be very romantic, but if we can talk love afterwards, I don't mind!
なんか内容が恋人っぽくないけど、その後恋を語ればいいわ
じゃあ海砂、今日はもう帰るんだ
Anyway, Misa, you'd better go home now.
Oh, what?! It's only 7pm!
え～なに、まだ七時じゃない
The time for lovers has only just begun!
恋人の時間はこれからです
二人でご飯食べて、夜景見て
We can go grab something to eat together, and follow that by watching the sun set, and then it'll be time to get serious!
その後がいよいよ本番って感じで…やぁ～♡
Misa.
海砂…
Okay?
いいな
For today, go home.
今日は帰るんだ
...Okay.
はい♡
Also, when you talk to Rem outside, make sure no one is around, and do so quietly.
それから、レムと外で会話する時は、
周りに人がいないか注意して、小声でた
I do the same with Ryuk.
僕もリュークとはそうしている
Okay...
はい…♡
Thank you for having me...
お邪魔しました～…
Misa-san! Please come again tomorrow!
海砂さん～明日も来てね
I was pretty surprised when you just kissed her out of nowhere.
しかし、いきなりキスとは驚いた
海砂には、僕に心底惚れさせておく必要がある
It's necessary to ensure that Misa falls utterly in love with me.
Oh...
More importantly, I need to decide whether or not to kill L tomorrow.
そんなことよりも、 L は明日殺すかどうかだ
Since Ryuuga's identity as L isn't publicly known, I've got to be prepared for the fact that if he dies, I will be strongly suspected of being Kira.
L として公になっていない今、流河が死ねば、
僕がキラだという疑いが濃厚になる事は、
覚悟しなければならない
Aah, I see.
なるほど
I thought that since you declared yourselves to be friends, you might be having second thoughts about killing him.
オレは「友達」とか言い出すから、
殺すのに躊躇しだしたのかと思ったぜ
"Friends"?
友達…？
話を合わせただけだ
I just went along with what he said.
最初から、「友情を求めてくるなら
受け入れてやろう」と、言っていたはずだ
From the beginning I've said, "if he wants friendship, I'll take it".
For Yagami Light, Ryuuga is merely a friend for appearance's sake.
流河は夜神月のうわべの友達
L is Kira's enemy.
L はキラの敵だ
That's right. L is my enemy.
そうだ… L は敵
Since he's revealed himself to me as L, I'll have to kill him...
流河が L と名乗った以上…殺すべき
ここで L に「事故死」を使えば、
僕をキラだと疑える者は殆ど居ない
If I make it an "accidental death", hardly anyone will suspect that I'm Kira, and even if they do, there'll be no proof.
居たとしても証拠などない
I can only imagine what will happen after L dies... this is now a gamble.
L が死んだ後の動きを想像しかできない…
もうここは賭けだ
Tomorrow, L... or rather Ryuuzaki or Ryuuga, will be your last.
明日が L …
いや、少なくとも
竜崎．流河の命日だ…
Hair.
毛
Crumbs from snacks.
スナック菓子食べカス
Hair.
毛
Yagami-san?
夜神さん
If I die in the next few days, your son is Kira.
近日中私が死んだら、息子さんがキラです
Hair again.
また毛
What did you just say, Ryuuzaki?!
今なんと言った竜崎…!!
That's right! Where's this suddenly coming from?
そうですよ、何を言い出すんです
I'll arrange it so that you can use Watari as you please.
ワタリを自由に使えるようにしておきますから、
The rest will be up to you.
あとはお願いします
Ryuuzaki! You said that the majority of your suspicions had already been dismissed!
竜崎…
殆ど疑いは晴れたと言っておいて、
How deeply do you really suspect my son?!
一体、本心ではどこまで息子を…
I'm not sure I really understand what I truly think myself.
私にも私の本心がわかりません
Nothing like this has ever happened before...
こんなこと今までなかった
If Kira and the second Kira have indeed made contact... I'm in a dire pinch.
キラと第二のキラが繋がったとすれば…
私は、大ピンチです
If Kira and the second Kira have indeed made contact... I'm in a dire pinch.
Thus, right now, I'm probably incapable of calmly analyzing myself.
ですから自分を、
冷静に分析できなくなっているのかもしれません
I could be doing this solely because I have no other suspects.
他に疑える者がいないから、固執しているだけかもしれない
Nevertheless, if I am killed now, please conclude that your son is Kira.
それでも…
今私が殺されたら、息子さんがキラだっ断定してください
Nevertheless, if I am killed now, please conclude that your son is Kira.
I'll have to make another surprise attack, but it can't be helped... this is now a gamble.
また不意打ちをすることになるが、仕方ない
もう…ここは賭けだ
That's not true, I'm just pretty sharp.
そんな事ないよ
ちょっと要領がいいだけさ
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
あっ、夜神君
Ah! Yagami-kun... hi.
こんにちは
Takada-san, I'd like to speak to him alone for a bit.
高田さん
ちょっと彼と二人で話がしたいんで、また後で
I'll see you later.
Huh? Okay...
え？あ、はい…
Sure this is okay? What about her?
いいんですか？彼女
Never mind that. You said you were "scared of showing your face in public", are you okay?
そんなことより、
「人前に顔を出すのは怖い」と言っていたのに、大丈夫なのか？
Yagami-kun, I realized I'd be fine as long as you're not Kira.
夜神君がキラでなければ大丈夫だと気付きました
Outside, you're the only one who knows I'm L.
外で私が L だと知っているのは夜神君だけですから
That's why, if I'm killed within the next few days... you are Kira. I've informed everyone at Headquarters of that fact.
なのでもし私が近日殺されたら、
「夜神月がキラ」だと本部の皆さんに言っておきました
That's why, if I'm killed within the next few days... you are Kira. I've informed everyone at Headquarters of that fact.
You!
コイツ…
夜神君も私の休学を寂しいと言ってくれましたし、
You said yourself that it's lonely without me around, so I thought I'd come in for a change of scenery.
少しは気分転換に来ることに…
死ななきゃ大学は楽しい所です
As long as I don't die, university is fun.
Yeah, when you're not around, there's no one I can talk to at my level. It's boring.
ああ、流河がいないと、
話のレベルが会う奴がいなくで、つまらないよ
Yeah, when you're not around, there's no one I can talk to at my level. It's boring.
And thus the talented Takada-san?
それで才女の高田さんですか
Well, something like that.
まぁ、そんなところだ
Will it really be safe to kill him today?
本当に今日…コイツを殺して大丈夫なのか…
No, by non-chalantly turning up like this, he's just trying to break my will to kill him.
いや…コイツ、殺そうと思ったところにノコノコ出てきて、
僕の決心をにぶらせている
おそらく、釘を刺しておく為に…
He's probably trying to warn me off.
This is just what he wants to happen...
これじゃコイツの思う壺じゃないか
Shall we grab some cake from the cafeteria?
学食でケーキ食べませんか？
Yeah, I got no lectures next period.
ああ、僕も次が休講なんだ
That's good.
それはよかった
I wonder if they have shortcake?
ショートケーキありますかね
Don't know, I can't remember.
さぁ…どうだったな
Light! There you are!
ライト、いた
I had a shoot nearby, so I thought I'd drop by!
この近くで撮影やってるから、来ちゃった
Misa... you idiot!
海砂!!馬鹿…
Light, one of your friends?
ライトのお友達？
Wow, he's wonderfully unique, isn't he...
個性的で素敵ね
No wait... I've won!
いや、勝った
Misa can see Ryuuga's real name!
海砂には流河の本名が見えている…
I'm Light's girlfriend, Amane Misa. Nice to meet you.
私、ライトの彼女の弥海砂、よろしくね
流河旱樹です
I'm Ryuuga Hideki.
Huh? Ryuuga Hideki?
え？
流河旱樹…
Yeah, he's got the same name as the idol. Funny, huh?
ああコイツ、あのアイドルと同姓同名なんだ
面白いだろ
But... that's different from the name I can see...
でも、見えてる名前と違う…
Ryuuga, this time, your decision to come out has worked against y--!
流河、今回は出てきたことが裏目に…
えへへ、えへ…
What's he laughing about?!
なんだその笑いは…
Don't tell me, he's realized?!
まさかコイツ…気付いたのか
But if he thinks there's a possibility that she's the second Kira, surely he wouldn't be able to laugh like that...
しかし、
第二のキラの可能性を考えたら、笑っていられるはずが…
Yagami-kun...
夜神君…
I'm very jealous.
羨ましいです
I've been a fan of Misa's since the August edition of "Eighteen".
「エイティーン」八月号からの海砂さんのファンです
Yay! Really?! I'm happy!
ええ本当、嬉しい
That girl, it's Misa-Misa, isn't it?!
あっ、あの子、ミサミサじゃない～？
You're right! It is Misa-Misa!
本当だ、ミサミサだ
Eh?! Misa-Misa?!
え、ミサミサ
Eh?! Really?!
え、本物？
やっぱり若い人多いとバレちゃうんだ
I always seem to get noticed when there's lots of young people around!
すごい
I buy your stuff every month!
毎月見てます
Please keep up the good work!
頑張ってください
Thanks, I'll try my best.
うん、ありがとう、頑張るよ
What's going on here?
なんなんだ…
No! Someone just touched my butt!
やだ！誰かお尻触った？
あ…
What nerve! To take advantage of all this confusion to do something like that!
何で不謹慎な
どさくさにまぎれて許せないですね
I'll find the culprit!
犯人は私が見つけます
あははは…流河君って面白い…
Ryuuga-san, you're so funny!
俺も触りてぇ
I wanna feel too.
Dumb-ass...
バカ
I want to find out L's real name from Misa as soon as possible, but with all these people around...
どうかが、早く海砂から L の本名を聞き出したいが、
この取り巻きが邪魔だ
Misa! It's time to go.
MISA ☆
もう時間よ、また遅刻する気？
Do you want to be late, again?
Sorry, Yoshii.
あっ…ごめんヨッシー
Let's go.
いくわよ
う、うん…
No matter.
いいぞ…
海砂がここから出ていけば、
あとは電話一本で名前を聞き出せる…
Even if Misa leaves, all I need to do is make one phone call to find out.
Bye Light! See you after work!
じゃあね、ライト
仕事終わったらね
Well then, shall we go, Yagami-kun?
さて、行きましょうか夜神君
Yeah.
ああ
You go ahead, I need to go to the toilet.
悪いが先に行っててくれ、トイレ寄っていくから
Really? Okay then.
そうですか？じゃあ…
It's over.
終わりだ
It's been all sorts of fun, L.
色々楽しかったよ、 L …
I'm so glad I was able to find out your real name and kill you myself.
お前の名前を知って、自分で殺せてよかった…
It's been all sorts of fun, L.
L 、色々楽しかったよ
I'm so glad I was able to find out your real name and kill you myself.
お前の名前を知って、自分で殺せてよかった…
Yes, hello?
はい、もしもし
What do you mean, "Hello"?
何が「もしもし」だ
It looks like someone dropped this phone amid all the confusion just now.
あ～この携帯、さっきの騒ぎの時誰かが落としたみたいです
At that time... he...
アイツ…
あの時…
Hello?
もしもし？
That's Misa's phone. I'll return it to her.
あ、それは海砂の携帯だから、僕が返しておくよ
Really? Okay, got it.
あっそうですか、わかりました
Ryuuga, you may think you've outwitted me, but Misa has another cell phone.
流河、「してやったり」と思ってるんだろうが
海砂はもう一つ携帯を持っている
Once I ring that...
そっちに掛ければ…
This time it's my cell phone.
今度は私の携帯です
はい
Yes?
はい、そうですか、やりましたね
Ah, is that right. We've done it, then.
Understood.
わかりました
This is probably both good and bad news for you.
夜神君にとっては嬉しかったり悲しかったりだと思いますが、
We've apprehended Amane Misa on suspicion of being the second Kira.
弥海砂を第二のキラ容疑で確保しました
Since when has he suspected Misa?!
一体いつから海砂の事を…
I can't believe she was caught so fast...
こんなに早く捕まるとは…
When the second Kira sent the video tapes from Amane's room,
弥の部屋から第二のキラがビデオテープを送った時、
they left a great deal of evidence, such as hairs and clothing fibres, stuck to packing tape used to seal the envelopes.
封をしていたガムテープに付着していた
毛や洋服の繊維など、多数の証拠が出ました
We believe that announcing she's under suspicion of being the second Kira would cause public chaos,
第二のキラ容疑ということでは世間の混乱が予想されるので、
マネジャーの麻薬所持容疑への任意同行にしていますが…
so we're saying she's gone to be questioned about the charges held against her manager for drug possession.
世間に出る事はないでしょう
However, I doubt the public will find that out.
I was too naive.
甘かった…
Those videos... I should have ensure I destroyed the evidence.
あのビデオ…僕が徹底的に証拠隠滅しておくべきだった…
結局流河は、隠れることよりも、
僕と一緒にいることで身を守り、確信に迫った…
In the end, by being around me, rather than hiding, Ryuuga managed to protect himself, and get right to the heart of the case...
This gamble... I've...
この賭け、僕の…
I've...
私の…
僕の…
No!
いや！
It's not over yet.
まただ…
The fight has just begun, L.
まだ勝負はこれからだ、 L
Watari, has she said anything yet?
ワタリ、何か喋ったか？
No, not a word.
いえ、まだ一言も…
Bring a visual of her up.
彼女の影像をこっちにもくれ
Are you sure?
いいんですか？
Yes, hurry up.
いいから、早く
R-Ryuuzaki... what the hell is this?!
竜…竜崎、これは一体…
She's been apprehended on suspicion of being the second Kira.
第二のキラとして捕まえたんです
これくらい当たり前です
It's only natural to take these precautions.
It's true that there was enough evidence in Amane's room to assure us that she's the second Kira...
確かに、弥の部屋には、
第二のキラと確信できるだけの証拠はあったが…
Yes, there's no doubt.
はい、間違えないでしょう
Now, we need a confession of how she kill people, if she knows Kira, and if she knows who Kira is.
あとはどう殺したのか、キラを知っているのか、
知っているなら誰なのか、
Now, we need a confession of how she kill people, if she knows Kira, and if she knows who Kira is.
自供させるしかありません
Watari, as long as you're careful, I won't mind if you use slightly dubious methods.
ワタリ、十分に注意しながら
多少理不尽なやり方でも構いません
Watari, as long as you're careful, I won't mind if you use slightly dubious methods.
Get her to spit it out.
吐かせて下さい
Okay.
はい
And, Yagami-san, please prepare yourself for the fact that I'll be bringing Light-kun in for questioning regarding Kira.
それで夜神さん
月君をキラとしての重要参考人で
呼ぶことになると思うので…覚悟しておいてください
Ryuuzaki! Amane has said something.
竜崎、弥が言葉を
Hurry and bring up a visual.
早く、影像と音声を！
Finally! After three days.
三日目にしてようやくか…
I can't stand it anymore...
もう…我慢できない…
Kill me.
殺して…
Kill me! Hurry up and kill me.
殺して…早く殺して
I thought it might have been too much for a girl who's only around twenty.
はたち
やはり…二十歳そこそこの女の子には厳しすぎる…
This must be her limit.
もう極限状態なんだ
Amane Misa, can you hear me?
弥海砂、聞こえるか？
I can hear you.
聞こえる…
お願い…早く殺して…
Please... hurry up and kill me.
Does that mean that you admit you are the second Kira?
それは自分が第二のキラであると認めるということか
No. I don't know anything about the second Kira...
違う…第二のキラなんて知らない…
I can't take this anymore... I'd rather die.
こんなのもう…我慢できない……死んだ方がいい…
Come on! Hurry up and kill me!
さあ！早く殺して！
I know you could kill me in an instant if you wanted to!
あなたなら私をすぐ殺せるでしょう！
Misa... you don't mean...
海砂…まさか…
そう…殺して…
That's right, kill me...
...you want me to kill you?
私に殺してくれと…
Yes, kill me.
そう…殺してよ
もう…我慢できない…
I can't endure this anymore, kill me.
殺して…
If I kill you, I'll kill Yagami Light too.
海砂を殺すなら夜神月を殺す
This is all his faul--
こんな事になったのも…
No! No!
ダメ…ダメ…私を殺して…
Kill me.
海砂そんなに…
Misa... you're really willing to die for him?
アイツの為に死ぬなんて…
That's enough! If you won't kill me I--
もういい…殺してくれないなら…！
Oh no!
まずい！ワタリ、舌をかませるな
Watari! Don't let her bite her tongue!
Surely, she's not being manipulated by Kira just before she dies?
まさかもうキラに操られての死の前の行動じゃないでしょうね…
おっ、レム
Hey Rem, what do you want all of a sudden?
なんだいきなり
Yagami Light, even though I offered to help Misa escape, she refused.
夜神月
海砂は私が逃がしてやると言っても拒絶した
Yagami Light, even though I offered to help Misa escape, she refused.
It's probably because she realized that she would be seen as having special powers, which would cause you trouble...
ちから
自分に特別な能力が備わっていると思われて、
オマエに迷惑がかかると思ったからだろう
And when she realized she was reaching the limits of her mentality, she began to ask for me to kill her.
そして精神的に限界が来たとみると
私に「殺してくれ」と頼み始めた
And when she realized she was reaching the limits of her mentality, she began to ask for me to kill her.
All this, because she wants to be loved by you.
全部、オマエに愛されたいが為だ
Even though she begged me to, there's no way I could kill Misa.
いくら頼まれても、そんな海砂を殺せない
見ていられなかった…
I couldn't bear to watch her suffer like that.
There's only one way to save her.
この苦しみから救い出す方法はひとつ…
Forfeiting ownership of the Death Note?
デスノートの所有権を放棄…
That's right.
そうだ
Once you forfeit ownership of a Death Note, all the memories you have of it disappears completely.
デスノートの所有権を放棄すれば、
デスノートに関する記憶が一切消える
Once you forfeit ownership of a Death Note, all the memories you have of it disappears completely.
She would forget about all the people she's killed, and the fact that Yagami Light is Kira.
自分のノートによる殺人も、
夜神月がキラであるという記憶もなくなり、
She would forget about all the people she's killed, and the fact that Yagami Light is Kira.
So, there would be no danger of her giving away your secret.
秘密が海砂から洩れる事はなくなる
Also, she would no longer be able to see Ryuk or myself.
そして海砂にはもう、私もリュークも見えなくなる…
A few hours earlier
Misa, this means that you'll forget everything you know about Shinigami.
海砂
お前が死神のことは、一切忘れる事になる
Misa, this means that you'll forget everything you know about Shinigami.
It's okay.
大丈夫だ、海砂の好きな人間は夜神月
The human you love is Yagami Light. Those feelings alone will remain.
その感情だけは残る…
That is why you should give up ownership of your Death Note and entrust everything to Yagami Light.
だから海砂、ノートの所有権を放棄して
全て夜神月に託せ
Misa is no longer the owner of a Death Note.
今もう海砂は、デスノートの所有者じゃない
Good work, Rem.
よくやってくれた、レム
I was just thinking that that was our sole option.
僕もその方法しかないと思っていたところだ…
If Misa has no memory of the Death Note, it's possible that she can be released.
デスノートの記憶が飛べば、
海砂を釈放させることも不可能じゃない
If Misa has no memory of the Death Note, it's possible that she can be released.
Yagami Light, I knew that this would be the best option for you, which is why I suggested it to Misa.
夜神月、今のオマエにとっては、
これが一番望ましい方法だとわかっていて、
Yagami Light, I knew that this would be the best option for you, which is why I suggested it to Misa.
私は海砂に提案した…
If you don't save Misa, I will kill you.
海砂を助け出さなければ、オマエを殺す
グフッ
I understand, Rem.
わかったよ、レム
これからの L の出方は大体わかっている
I've got a fair idea of what L might do from here, and I have a plan.
僕に考えがある…
This is goodbye, Ryuk.
さよならだ、リューク
Huh?
えっ!?
To be continued
ああ…自分でも格好のいい状態とは思えないが…
そんなくだらないプライドは…
捨てる！